The Evil of the Daleks(Episode 3)
《Daleks 的邪恶》 (第三部分)
Doctor Who (1963) 04x09c
原为《神秘博士》老版第四季第九集
【时间轴/翻译】巴蛮子sz
（注意：此字幕的时间轴按2021动画重制版重新调整）
基于 opentitles.org 英文字幕翻译
Sincro: wyxchari
DALEK 1: The humans have been told to begin the test.
已经通知人类开始实验
DALKE 2: Any delay will result in death.
任何人拖延都将被处死
DALEK 2: There will be no delay!
不允许有拖延!
- WATERFIELD: Mollie, Mollie.
- MAXTIBLE: Mr. McCrimmon has been kidnapped!
Mollie, Mollie. McCrimmon先生被绑架了!
- MAXTIBLE: It means the end of us.
- WATERFIELD:  Unless we can find him quickly.
- 这意味着我们完蛋了  - 除非我们能赶紧找到他
- DOCTOR: Straw.   - WATERFIELD: I beg your pardon?
- 稻草  - 你说什么?
DOCTOR: A piece of straw.
一小截稻草
TOBY: Had a cosy little sleep, young swell?
小觉睡的还舒服吧, 年轻人?
TOBY: Lively, is it? Maybe you'd like to sleep again?
醒了吧, 对不? 是不是还想睡一觉?
TOBY: I've got Mr. Nod here. He'll have you snorin' as good as ever.
我这里有位“点头”先生, 他会让你的呼噜震天响的
JAMIE: What do you want?
你想要怎么样?
TOBY: I'm to be well paid. Have no fear of that.
我会得到很好的报酬, 我不怕那个
JAMIE: Oh, and for what? I don't know you.
哦, 得到什么报酬?  我不认识你
TOBY: This your man, sir?
这是你要的人, 先生?
TERRALL: Toby! What in Hades have you done?
Toby! 你到底干了什么?
TOBY: Why, I brought 'im from the house, like you said.
怎么了, 我把他从房子里带过来了啊, 正如你说的
TERRALL: I said nothing of the kind.
我可没说这样的话
TOBY: Well ya did, sir! Honest ya did.
你说过, 先生! 你真的说过
TOBY: A guinea ya promised me.
许诺给我一几尼呢
TOBY: I done what ya said. You don't get outta payin'.
我已经做了你要求的, 你别想不付钱
TERRALL: Be careful how you speak to me, Toby!
注意你跟我说话的方式, Toby!
TERRALL: There's your money. Get out!
这是给你的钱, 出去!
TERRALL: Where's Toby?
Toby 哪儿去了?
JAMIE: You just sent him about his business.
你刚把他打发走了啊
JAMIE: Look, what's the matter? Are you all right?
嘿, 这怎么回事? 你没事吧?
TERRALL: Where's Victoria Waterfield?
Victoria Waterfield 在哪儿?
JAMIE: I don't know.
我不知道
- TERRALL: Yes, you do.
- JAMIE: I tell you, I don't even know her!
- 你知道  - 我跟你说, 我都不认识她
TERRALL: You're in the house, a friend of Maxtible's.
You must know!
你在这个房子里, 你是 Maxtible 的朋友, 你肯定知道!
JAMIE: No, listen, I'm telling...
不, 听着, 我说的是...
TERRALL: Ha, I must apologize for that villain Toby.
哈, 我必须为那个恶棍 Toby 的事向你道歉
TERRALL: He was telling lies, of course.
I shall escort you to the house.
当然, 他说的都是谎言. 我护送你回房子里去
JAMIE: Uh, You.... you just asked me about Victoria Waterfield.
哦, 你...你刚才还在问我 Victoria Waterfield 的事情
TERRALL: Oh, she's in Paris.
噢, 她还在巴黎呢
TERRALL: I'm afraid I haven't introduced myself - Arthur Terrall.
恐怕我还没有介绍我自己 - Arthur Terrall
JAMIE: Well, never mind about that.  Did you or did you not...
哦, 先别说这个. 你有还是没有...
JAMIE: ask that man to knock me on the head and bring me in here?
...叫那个人把我打晕, 再把我带到这里来?
TERRALL: I, oh...certainly not!
我...当然没有啊
JAMIE: Doctor
博士
TERRALL: Oh. I see you're in good hands now.
I won't detain you any further.
哦, 我看你现在碰到朋友了. 我就不再耽误你了.
- TERRALL: Good day, Doctor.   - DOCTOR: Oh, good day to you.
- 日安, 博士  - 哦, 你也日安
JAMIE: He's mad. Stark, staring mad!
他疯了, 他完全疯了
DOCTOR: Yes, I know. I was listening.
是的, 我知道, 刚才我听到了
- DOCTOR: Let's have a look at that head of yours. Come along.
- JAMIE: Look, it's all right, Doctor.
- 我们来看看你的头吧, 过来  - 哦, 没事的, 博士
JAMIE: One minute he says this,
the next minute he says that.
前一分钟他在说这个, 后一分钟他又说那个
JAMIE: Can you make it out, Doctor?
你能搞明白吗, 博士?
JAMIE: I'm knocked on the head and I'm brought in here.
我被人敲晕了脑袋, 带到了这里
JAMIE: Then that man Terrall enters
and denies having ordered the other man to do it.
那个Terrall 进来这里, 又否认是他让那个人干的
JAMIE: Well, then he changes, and starts
asking about Victoria Waterfield
然后, 他又变了, 开始问 Victoria Waterfield 的事情,
JAMIE: And in the next breath, he tells me she's in Paris!
下一秒钟他又告诉我她在巴黎!
DOCTOR: I know what's happened to Victoria.
我知道 Victoria 发生了什么事
JAMIE: What has?
什么事?
DOCTOR: She's a prisoner of the Daleks.
她成了 Daleks 的囚徒
DALEK: Hurry!
快点!
VICTORIA: Why am I being moved?
为什么要转移我?
VICTORIA: Are you taking me back to my father?
你们要带我回到我父亲那里吗?
DALEK: No, you are being moved.
不, 是给你换个地方
DALEK: Pick up your cover.
带上你的外套
DALEK: Follow.
跟上
DALEK: Do not be afraid. You are not to be exterminated.
不用害怕, 你不会被终结掉
DALEK: Do not delay.
不要磨蹭
DALEK: Move.
走
WATERFIELD: You've warned him - told him about the Daleks?
你警告他了, 把 Daleks 的事情告诉他了?
- DOCTOR: Yes, of course I did!
- WATERFIELD: But you were expressly told...
- 是的, 我当然干了  - 但你被明令禁止...
DOCTOR: Oh, fiddlesticks! Bosh!
哦, 胡说! 放屁!
DOCTOR: Jamie will cooperate. You may be certain of that.
Jamie 会合作的. 这个事情你可以放心
- WATERFIELD: Are you sure?   - DOCTOR: Yes, certainly sure.
- 你确定吗?   - 是的, 当然确定
DOCTOR: Jamie will do everything he is asked to do.
让 Jamie 做任何事情, 他都会去做
JAMIE: Now come along, we must go and find Maxtible.
来吧, 我们得去找 Maxtible 了
DALEK: The female human being has been moved.
那个人类女性已经被转移
MAXTIBLE: Everything is prepared.
一切已经准备就绪
DALEK: The testing equipment is ready?
实验设备准备好了吗?
MAXTIBLE: I think you will be pleased with the man,
I've had specially brought from London.
我想你们会满意这个人, 我特意从伦敦带过来的
- MAXTIBLE: Ah, he works in my house.   - DALEK: Show me!
- 他在我房子里做事  - 给我看
MAXTIBLE: You will understand that he is rather simple.
你要明白他是一个相当简单的人
MAXTIBLE: He's quite dumb, but, uh... that has its advantages for us.
他很笨, 不过...对我们而言这有他的优势
MAXTIBLE: His mind is, how shall I say, undeveloped.
他的大脑, 怎么说呢, 不太发达
MAXTIBLE: He will not understand you, the Daleks.
他搞不懂你们 Daleks
- MAXTIBLE: Uh, I mean he will be terrified of you.   - DALEK: Show me!
- 我是说, 他是会害怕你们  - 给我看
MAXTIBLE: Ohh, I beg your pardon, uh...
哦, 我很抱歉
MAXTIBLE: Kemel!
Kemel!​
MAXTIBLE: Will you come with me?
你跟我来
MAXTIBLE: I want you to stand here.
我要你站在这里
MAXTIBLE: No, no, no, no, no, face the cabinet. Good.
不, 不, 不, 面朝柜子. 好了
MAXTIBLE: Now, bend that.
现在, 掰弯那个
MAXTIBLE: Excellent Kemel, excellent.
很好, Kemel, 很好
Now, you'll help me with these stools.
现在, 帮我摆一下这几个凳子
MAXTIBLE: Now, Kemel. One blow. Break the plank!
现在, Kemel, 一次, 打断这块木头!
MAXTIBLE: Very good Kemel. I'm very pleased with you.
很好, Kemel, 我对你很满意
MAXTIBLE: Now you can put on your jacket. Come over here.
现在你可以穿上你的夹克了. 到这里来
MAXTIBLE: Now, I want you to listen carefully. See this man?
现在, 我想要你听仔细了, 看到这个人了吗?
MAXTIBLE: Now, I'm going to take you to a place that I want you to guard,
现在, 我要带你去一个地方, 期望你做好守卫工作
MAXTIBLE: and this young man will try and get past you
而这个年轻人会试图越过你
and you are not to let him. Do you understand?
你不能允许他过去, 你明白吗?
MAXTIBLE: Oh, he's an evil villain, Kemel
哦, 他是一个邪恶的坏人, Kemel,
a cutthroat who would gladly murder us all in our beds, if he could.
他会残忍地将我们所有人杀死在床上, 如果他得到机会
MAXTIBLE: You will remember this man, hmm?
你要记住这个人, 嗯?
MAXTIBLE: Right. Well, you come with me and I will direct you.
好了, 你跟我来, 我带你去
MAXTIBLE: This is the entrance to the south wing of my house,
这里是我房子的南厢入口
MAXTIBLE: and through here will pass
the man I showed you in the picture.
图片里面那个人就会从这里过来
MAXTIBLE: The door itself is an obstacle.
这门就是一个屏障
MAXTIBLE: No, no, wait!
不, 不, 等等!
MAXTIBLE: Now, if he gets through here, you will deal with him.
现在, 如果他到这里来, 你要对付他
Go now.
去吧
DALEK: We do not trust you.
我们不信任你
DOCTOR: Then we're quits, aren't we?
那我们退出, 可以吗?
DALEK: But we have your time machine.
但你的时间机器在我们手上
DALEK: So, you will obey us.
所以, 你要服从我们
DOCTOR: They want the "Human Factor", is that right?
他们想要“人类特质”, 对吗?
WATERFIELD: Yes, that is what they want.
是的, 那就是他们想要的
DOCTOR: Very complex.
这很复杂
And you want to introduce
this "human factor" into the race of Daleks?
. 你们期望把“人类特质”加入到 Daleks 种族中去?
DALEK: Yes, the conquest of humanity has eluded us.
是的, 人类的征服能力让我们很困惑
DALEK: The Daleks must know why.
Daleks 必须明白为什么
DOCTOR: But, why choose Jamie for this test?
但是, 为什么挑选 Jamie 做这个实验?
DALEK: His travelling with you makes him unique.
他跟你一起旅行, 这让他变得独特
DOCTOR: But why him? Why not me?
但为什么是他, 为什么不是我?
- DALEK: Request denied.   - DOCTOR: Why?
- 拒绝回答  - 为什么?
DALEK: You have travelled too much through time.
You are more than human.
你在时间中旅行得太久了, 你不仅仅是个人类了
DOCTOR: I see.
我明白了
DOCTOR: What is this?
这是什么?
MAXTIBLE: They have been brought from the Dalek planet.
他们是从 Dalek 星球带过来的
- DOCTOR: Skaro!   - DALEK: Yes.
- Skaro(注: Daleks 的母星)  - 是的
DALEK: Their life force is dormant.
Before it is activated, we want...
他们目前处于休眠状态, 激活之前, 我们想...
DOCTOR: You want the "human factor" introduced. I see.
你们想要引入“人类特质”, 我知道了
DALEK: You will obey us!
你要服从我们!
DOCTOR: I will make up my own mind!
我会自己拿主意!
MAXTIBLE: Do not antagonize them, Doctor.
They will destroy your time machine!
不要激怒他们, 博士. 他们会毁了你的时间机器的!
MAXTIBLE: And if I agree, it means the creation of a race of super-Daleks!
但如果我同意, 那就意味着超级 Daleks 的诞生!
DOCTOR: My TARDIS... I have no choice, do I?
我的 TARDIS...我没有选择, 有吗?
DOCTOR: Very well. I agree.
好吧, 我同意了
DALEK: The human being with you must not be aware of the trial.
跟着你的那个人必须对这项实验不知情
DOCTOR: I quite understand.
我很明白
DALEK: Make him begin the test!
让他开始实验!
DOCTOR: What must Jamie do?
Jamie 必须干什么?
MAXTIBLE: Attempt to rescue Waterfield's daughter.
尝试营救 Waterfield 的女儿
- MOLLIE: There we are, sir.   - RUTH: Thank you, Mollie.
- 就是这里, 先生 - 谢谢你, Mollie
RUTH: Arthur, I'd like you to meet Mr. McCrimmon.
Arthur, 我引你见一下 McCrimmon 先生
TERRALL: May I ask what you are doing in this house?
我能问问你在这个房子里面干什么吗?
JAMIE: I was just about to ask you the same thing.
我也正要问你同一个问题
RUTH: Oh, you gentlemen have been introduced?
哦, 有人已经介绍两位先生认识了?
JAMIE: Aye, we've met.
是, 我们见过面
TERRALL: It seems, Ruth, your father has the
oddest collection of house guests these days.
看起来, Ruth 小姐, 你父亲这几天招待了一大堆奇怪的客人啊
RUTH: Now Arthur, please!
Arthur, 别这样
RUTH: You must forgive him, Mr. McCrimmon.
你得原谅他, McCrimmon 先生
JAMIE: Ah, it's becoming a habit.
啊, 都已经习惯了
TERRALL: I don't care for insolence.
我并不太在意这些无礼的行为
JAMIE: Well, I'm not keen on arrogance myself!
哈, 我也不太在乎那些自大的家伙
RUTH: Why, you bite at each other as if you were old enemies!
为什么, 你们俩就好像宿敌一样要互相咬?
JAMIE: I'm sorry if I seem rude.
如果我看起来比较无礼, 我很抱歉
RUTH: Come, I want you to be friends.
Won't you be so, to please me?
好了, 我期望你们成为朋友. 你们可以吗, 就给我点面子?
RUTH: Arthur... Arthur, what is it?
Arthur... Arthur, 怎么了?
RUTH: Excuse me.
抱歉
RUTH: Arthur! What's the matter?
Arthur! 什么情况?
- MOLLIE: Sir?   - Yes?!
- 先生?    - 什么事?
JAMIE: Oh, I wish you'd call me Jamie.
哦, 我期望你叫我 Jamie
MOLLIE: Oh, I couldn't do that sir. What would the master say?
噢, 我不能那样做, 先生. 不知道主人会怎么说我呢
JAMIE: Oh, who cares! Ah, What can I do for you?
哦, 谁在乎! 啊, 有什么能帮到你的?
MOLLIE: If you'd tell me where your bags are, sir - yours and the Doctor's
如果你能告诉我你的包裹在哪儿 —— 你的和博士的
MOLLIE: I'll have them taken up to your room.
我会让人把他们带到你的房间来的
JAMIE: Aye. well, Mollie...
啊, 这个, Mollie...
MOLLIE: Listen to me, "have them taken. "
I dare say I'll be doin' it meself!
听我说, 我说“让人带过来”, 其实我会亲自做的!
JAMIE: You see, we didn't have time to
pick up the luggage. It'll be following.
你看, 我们并没有时间收拾行李, 过两天才会送来
MOLLIE: Oh.
哦
JAMIE: Why do you say that you'll be doing it yourself?
为什么你说你要自己做?
MOLLIE: Well, they do say, sir, that the house is haunted.
哦, 他们说, 先生, 这房子闹鬼
MOLLIE: Mr. Kitson, the butler, left.
Kitson 先生, 我们的管家离开了
MOLLIE: And cook and the two footmen are complainin' again.
厨师和两个杂役都在说这个
- JAMIE: Haunted?  -  MOLLIE: Mmm. But, I've never heard anything sir.
- 闹鬼?    - 嗯. 不过, 我从来没听到过什么, 先生
MOLLIE: I sleep like a log and always have.
我睡觉跟一根木头似的, 总是这样
JAMIE: Aye. well, I'm glad you've got over the fright you had.
啊, 我很高兴你已经克服了恐惧
JAMIE: Oh, yes, that horrible man.
噢, 是的, 那个吓人的家伙
MOLLIE: Miss Ruth said it was all a game, but I dunno sir.
Ruth 小姐说只是个游戏, 不过我也搞不懂.
MOLLIE: I've never fainted before, sir. Truly I haven't.
我以前从来没有晕倒过, 先生. 真的没有
JAMIE: Not "sir", "Jamie"!
不是“先生”, 叫我“Jamie”!
JAMIE: Tell me about Arthur Terrall.
告诉我一些 Arthur Terrall 的情况
MOLLIE: Miss Ruth's fiance, sir?
Ruth 小姐的未婚夫吗, 先生
MOLLIE: Oh, oh, he's a kind man, sir. Usually.
哦, 他是个好人, 先生. 通常来说
JAMIE: Usually?
通常来说?
MOLLIE: Mmm. Well, when he's a bit odd or his temper's up,
as it has been lately,
嗯, 就是, 他有点怪, 或者脾气上来了, 就像最近那样
MOLLIE: I says to meself "Inkerman" and then it's all right.
我跟自己说, 估计“英克曼人”就是那样
- JAMIE: "Inkerman"?   - MOLLIE: Yes sir.
- “英克曼人”?   - 是的先生
MOLLIE:  'e was out in the Crimea, 'e was.
他之前在克里米亚
MOLLIE: They do say Mr. Terrall was wounded out there.
他们的确说过 Terrall 在那里受了伤
MOLLIE: Do you know, my uncle was killed at Inkerman, sir.
你知道吗, 我叔叔就是在英克曼战死的, 先生
(备注：1854-1856年, 俄国与英、法为争夺小亚细亚地区权利而爆发“克里米亚战争“)
MOLLIE: So, you see, I do know what it's like with soldiers.
所以, 你看, 我还真知道士兵是怎样的
(备注：1854-1856年, 俄国与英、法为争夺小亚细亚地区权利而爆发“克里米亚战争“)
- MOLLIE: Oh... oh, I'm sorry sir. I didn't mean to...
- DOCTOR: Never mind. Mollie.
- 噢, 对不起先生. 我不是有意的...  - 没事的, Mollie
MOLLIE: Well cook said to me that
if I did some dusting it would be all right.
厨师跟我说, 我打扫打扫就可以了
MOLLIE: Oh, you won't tell the master, will you?
哦, 你不会告诉主人的, 是吗?
- DOCTOR: I wouldn't dream of telling him.
- MOLLIE: Thank you. Sorry sir.
- 我不会告诉他的  - 谢谢你, 对不起,先生
DOCTOR: Thank you very much, Bye-bye.
很谢谢你, 拜拜
DOCTOR: Hmm, you'll have to brush up on your history.
你得刷新一下你的历史知识了
DOCTOR: I can't be around to cover up for you all the time.
我不可能总在你身边帮你补课
(备注: Jamie 是172x年诞生的, 174x年开始跟随博士旅行, 所以他对后面的历史知道得不多)
DOCTOR: Now then, in the Crimean War, the English, the French
and the Turks fought the Russians...
这一次, 克里米亚战争, 英国人、法国人和土耳其人一起跟俄国人打
- JAMIE: Oh, forget about all that!
- DOCTOR: Oh, I thought you'd be interested.
- 哦, 忘了那些吧  - 哦, 我还以为你感兴趣
DOCTOR: I watched the Charge of the Light Brigade. Magnificent folly...
我可见过轻骑兵发起的冲锋, 那可真是愚蠢...
(备注: 此处特指1854年10月克里米亚战争巴拉克拉瓦战役中,
英国轻骑兵向俄军发起的冲锋, 因命令传达错误而伤亡惨重.
因诗歌 The Charge of the Light Brigade 而受后人铭记)
DOCTOR: Look, where've you been?
我说, 你都去哪儿了?
DOCTOR: Oh, just looking around.
哦, 只是四处看看
JAMIE: Aye. What for? The TARDIS?!
啊, 看什么? TARDIS 吗?
DOCTOR: Jamie, you're in a temper!
Jamie, 你在闹脾气啊
JAMIE: Oh, am I? Is that bad then?
哦, 是吗? 这很糟糕吧?
JAMIE: Does that mean I won't be co-operative
是不是意味着我不会乖乖听话了?
- JAMIE: I won't do everything I'm told?   - DOCTOR: What was that?
- 不会说什么我就做什么了?  - 这是怎么了?
JAMIE: I overheard you and Waterfield!
我听到了你和 Waterfield 的对话!
- DOCTOR: You were eavesdropping!
-JAMIE: Well, whatever it is, I don't like what you're doing.
- 你居然在偷听!   - 不管怎样, 我不喜欢你现在做的事
- DOCTOR: Now you listen to me...!   - JAMIE: No, Doctor,
- 你听我说...!   - 不了, 博士
JAMIE: You're forgetting the TARDIS was stolen and a man was murdered!
你已经忘记 TARDIS 被偷了, 还有人被杀了
JAMIE: Now, how am I supposed to tell when I see
you as friendly as you like with the murderer!
现在, 我看见你跟杀人凶手在一起跟朋友似的, 你让我怎么想呢?
DOCTOR: Waterfield did not murder that man!
Waterfield 没有杀那个人!
JAMIE: All right then, but he stole the TARDIS
and that still makes him a thief!
那好, 但他偷了 TARDIS, 他仍然还是一个小偷!
- DOCTOR: The Daleks forced him to!
- The Daleks! You keep telling me about the Daleks,
- Daleks 强迫他干的!   - Daleks!  你一直跟我说 Daleks
JAMIE: and I haven't even seen one!
但我一个没见着!
JAMIE: You're always on about them, but where are they?!
你总叨叨他们, 但他们在哪儿呢?
- DOCTOR: Now you listen to me...!
- JAMIE: No, you'll not get round me this time, Doctor.
- 你听我说!  - 不, 这次你别想忽悠我了, 博士
JAMIE: You're up to something with Waterfield and Maxtible.
你跟 Waterfield 还有 Maxtible 在搞些什么
JAMIE: Now what is it? Some scientific invention?!
到底是什么呢? 某种科学发明吗? !
JAMIE: Ah, here's your friend.
啊, 你的朋友来了
DOCTOR: Just a little argument.
只是一点小争论
WATERFIELD: I heard voices raised.
我听着声音有点大了
JAMIE: That's not all you'll hear!
你能听见的才不止这点呢
DOCTOR: Jamie seems to think that I'm lying to him.
Jamie 似乎认为我在欺骗他
JAMIE: Well, aren't you?!
怎么, 没有吗?
DOCTOR: He doesn't believe the Daleks are here.
他并不相信 Daleks 就在这里
WATERFIELD: It's the truth.
这是事实
JAMIE: Aye, the truth you told Arthur Terrall, maybe
对, 事实, 你告诉 Arthur Terrall 的也是事实
- JAMIE: that your daughter was in Paris!
- WATERFIELD: I had to tell him that.
- 说你的女儿在巴黎!   - 我只能那样跟他说
JAMIE: So, you've got another story to tell me?
所以你还有另外一个故事是给我的罗?
WATERFIELD: I tell you that the Daleks are holding my daughter prisoner
我跟你说, 我女儿现在就囚禁着我女儿
WATERFIELD: in the south wing of this house, Mr. McCrimmon.
就在这栋房子的南面, McCrimmon 先生
JAMIE: Then why don't you try and get her back, eh?!
What are you doing?!
那你怎么不试着把她救回来, 嗯? 你在忙些什么?
DOCTOR: Well, what can I do? Now, be... be fair Jamie.
我能怎么做? 你看...得讲点道理啊 Jamie
DOCTOR: Waterfield's tied hand and foot because of his daughter
Waterfield 因为他女儿而投鼠忌器
DOCTOR: and we're tied hand and foot because of the TARDIS!
而我们因为 TARDIS 而束手束脚
JAMIE: Aye, and that's all you can
think about, isn't it? The TARDIS?
啊, 你能想到的就只有这个, TARDIS, 是吗?
JAMIE: Well, you can all stand around doing nothing.
I'm sick to death of it!
你就站在那里什么也不做? 我恶心死了!
DOCTOR: Now just where are you going?
你现在要去哪儿?
JAMIE: To be by myself for a bit. Do you mind?
一个人呆一会儿, 你管得着吗?
DOCTOR: No, not a bit. But, one word of warning.
不, 管不着. 但警告你一句话
DOCTOR: Don't you try to be a one-man army. You leave well alone.
别想一个人逞英雄. 你别管这事
DOCTOR: I won't have you ruining everything
trying to rescue Victoria Waterfield.
我不能允许你为了救 Victoria Waterfield 而毁了一切
DOCTOR: Now, you understand?!
你听明白了没有? !
WATERFIELD: Well, are you sure you didn't go a little too far, Doctor?
唉, 你确定这样是不是有点过火了, 博士?
DOCTOR: Adding a little fuel to the fire.
我给火上浇点油
DOCTOR: Tell Maxtible that I'll be along to his laboratory shortly.
告诉 Maxtible 我很快就到他的实验室去
- WATERFIELD: Oh, very well, Doctor. If you're sure.
- DOCTOR: Oh yes, quite sure.
- 好吧, 博士, 如果你确定的话  - 是的, 很确定
DOCTOR: Once our young friend has cooled
his heels a bit, he'll launch off on his own.
一旦我们的小朋友冷静一点, 他就会自己开始行动了
DOCTOR: And you dropped the hint about the south wing beautifully.
而且你也很漂亮地把南厢房的线索传递给他了
TERRALL: Well, what is it?
怎么, 什么事?
TERRALL: You wanted to see me?
你想要见我?
- TOBY: Very good of you to talk to me, gov'nor.
- TERRALL: Well, never mind all that.
- 你愿意跟我谈谈太好了, 先生  - 得, 别来这些了
TERRALL: I'll give you two minutes, no more.
我给你两分钟, 多了没有
TOBY: I want me rights. No more, no less.
我想争取我的权利, 不多要, 也不能少给
TERRALL: What do you mean, "rights"?
你什么意思, “权利”?
TOBY: 'alf a guinea, you gave me, and it ain't what we said.
你就给了半个基尼, 这不是我们之前说好的
TERRALL: You were lucky to get anything.
你还能拿到一点就不错了
- TOBY: That ain't fair!  - TERRALL: You'll get no more from me.
- 这不公平  - 你别想从我这里得到更多钱
TERRALL: I warn you! Keep away from
this house, and this property.
我警告你, 离这个房子远点儿
TERRALL: Find the nearest road to London and take it!
找到去伦敦的路, 走吧
TOBY: Oh, yeah, London, sir. Yeah.
哦, 好啊, 伦敦, 先生, 成
TOBY: I daresay I could earn something for me stories there.
我敢说, 到了那里我只凭讲故事就可以挣到钱啦
- TERRALL: Stories?
- TOBY: Oh, I won't detain an important gentleman like yourself.
- 故事?   - 我可不敢再耽误您这样的绅士了
TOBY: Like as not me two minutes is up anyway.
似乎我的两分钟已经到了
TERRALL: What do you mean, "stories"?
你什么意思, “讲故事”?
TOBY: Ah, it's all right, sir. I'll take a stroll to London...
啊, 没事, 先生. 我得上路去伦敦了. . .
TERRALL: Don't play with me!
别跟我玩花样!
TOBY: Get off me!
离我远点
TOBY: If you must know, there's plenty
who'd pay to hear what I've got to tell 'em.
如果你非得知道, 有好多人愿意付钱听我给他们讲呢
TERRALL: Indeed?
真的?
TOBY: Yeah. You blows too hot and cold for me
是啊, 你这一会儿阴一会儿晴
- tellin' me this one minute and that the next, and not payin' up.
一会儿跟我这么说, 一会儿又那么说, 还不付钱
TERRALL: You know nothing.
你什么也不知道
TOBY: Don't I though?
我不知道吗?
TERRALL: Hmm. Who'd believe you anyway?
唔, 谁会信你呢?
TOBY: Pay me off, and there's the end of it!
把钱付了, 这事儿就算完了
TERRALL: Oh, blackmail is it?! Get out!
噢, 勒索是吗?  滚出去!
TOBY: Maybe I don't know much to tell,
也许我知道得不多
TOBY: but I'll wager I'll find something
in the house that's worth me trouble.
但我打赌我能在这房子里找到点什么, 肯定有料
TOBY: So, I'll say thank ya, Mr. Terrall, sir!
那, 我就说声谢谢你了, Terrall 先生
JAMIE: It's only me, Mollie!
是我, Mollie!
MOLLIE: It's over here, sir. I took it from the master's study.
在这里了, 先生. 我从主人的书房里面拿出来的
JAMIE: It's marvellous. Thank you!
这太棒了, 谢谢你!
MOLLIE: 'ere, is this what you wanted?
这里, 这是你想要的吗?
JAMIE: Perfect, yes. Let's see, umm...
非常好, 好了, 让我来看看, 唔...
- JAMIE: This is the south wing here?   - MOLLIE: Yes, sir.
- 这里是南厢房吗?   - 是的, 先生
- MOLLIE: But it's been closed off.   - JAMIE: Completely?
- 但它被封起来了 - 完全封了?
MOLLIE: Oh, no sir. Only 'cause of some repairs
about a twelve-month back.
哦, 不是, 先生. 只是一些修缮工作, 都快一年了
MOLLIE: But the door may be locked.
不过门可能被锁住了
- JAMIE: Can you show me?  - MOLLIE: All right.
- 你能指给我看一下吗?   - 好吧
MOLLIE: What're you gonna do, sir?
你打算做什么, 先生?
JAMIE: Off to hunt a few wee ghosties, Mollie.
去抓几个小鬼, Mollie
DOCTOR: Every single one of Jamie's reactions
will be recorded on these Dalek machines?
而 Jamie 的每个动作都会在 Dalek 的这些机器上记录下来?
MAXTIBLE: And then transformed into thought patterns
on silver wire. A wonderful creation!
然后再转化成思维模型, 存储到银线. 多么漂亮的发明!
DALEK: It is for you, Doctor, to select the major feelings
to make up this "human factor".
然后要由博士你, 负责挑选出那些组成“人类特质”的主要情感
DOCTOR: Oh, yes. I quite understand.
哦, 是的, 我完全明白
MAXTIBLE: We can rely on the Doctor to give us all cooperation.
我们可以信赖博士给予我们全面的合作
DALEK: We shall watch your every move.
我们会盯着你的一举一动
DOCTOR: I'm sure you will.
我确信你们会的
DOCTOR: And every step of Jamie's progress will be covered?
Jamie 的每一步也会包含在内吧?
DALEK: Yes.
是的
DALEK: The young human being is on his way.
那个年轻的人类已经在路上了
DOCTOR: Then the recording machines can be set in action.
那么录制设备就可以开启了
- JAMIE: Here!   - MOLLIE: Yes, sir.
- 这里  - 是的, 先生
MOLLIE: I once remember the master stepping away from here.
我记得有一次主人就从这里走过去的
MOLLIE: When he saw me, he was very cross and told me to keep away.
他看见我的时候非常生气, 让我离开
JAMIE: I see.
我明白了
MOLLIE: What was that? What was that?!
什么声音? 那是什么声音?
JAMIE: That was no ghost, Mollie, that's for sure.
那不是鬼, Mollie, 这点可以肯定
- JAMIE: That was a human voice!   - MOLLIE: Oh, sir!
- 那是一个人的声音!   - 哦, 先生!
JAMIE: Look Mollie, take the candle and go back to your room.
Mollie, 拿着蜡烛, 回到你的房间去
- JAMIE: Will you do that?  - MOLLIE: Yes sir.
- 你可以吗?  - 可以先生
JAMIE: Now, do you want me to see you safely there?
你期望我陪你过去, 以确保你安全到达吗?
MOLLIE: No, no. I'll be all right.
不, 不用, 我没事的
Hello. Who are you?
JAMIE: 你好, 你是谁?